(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-29T21:03:46.504963",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ああ！ みんな 見てるー？
Ah! Everyone, are you watching?
大神ミオだよー！ わーー！
It's Ookami Mio! Whoa!
見てるかー！ 見て！ 見てるー！
Are you watching? Look! Are you watching?
お誕生日おめでとう！ ありがとう！ありがとう！ありがとうー！
Happy birthday! Thank you so much! Thank you!
はい、というわけで、えー 皆さんこんばんはミオです！大神ミオです！
Right, so, um, everyone, good evening! It's Ookami Mio!
ということで今日はうちの誕生日に、えー、ライブに来てくれて本当にどうもありがと！
So today, for my birthday, thank you so much for coming!
あ、スパチャもありがとう！メンバーシップもありがとう！見てるよ！
Ah, thanks for the super chats! Thanks for the memberships too!
見てるよ！ 見てるよーっ！ ありがとう！
I see you! I see you! Thank you!
ということで今日は歌ももちろんライブということでね、あるんだけど、
And so, today there will of course be singing and a live performance,
あの、まあいろんなね、ゲストが来てなんかね、おこる事件が起こるみたいなんでね！
various guests are coming and all sorts of things are gonna happen!
よかったら、ちょっとみんな最後まで見ててくれたら嬉しいなって思います！よろしくね！
So I hope you'll all stick around and watch until the end!
ではでは、さっそくですけど、1曲目からスタートしたいと思います！
Well then, without further ado, let's start with the first song!
1曲目！うちが大好きな曲です。
The first song! It's a song I really love.
プラチナ歌わせていただきます！
I'll be singing "Platinum"!
I’m a dreamer 潜むパワー
I'm a dreamer, a hidden power,
私の世界
my world
夢と恋と不安で出来てる
is built with dreams, love, and worries,
でも想像もしないもの 隠れてるはず
but things you'd never imagine must be hiding there.
空に向かう木々のようにあなたを
Like trees reaching toward the sky,
まっすぐ見つめている
I am looking straight at you.
みつけたいな かなえたいな
I want to find it, I want to make it true,
信じるそれだけで 越えられないものはない
just believing is enough to overcome anything.
歌うように 奇跡のように 「思い」が全てを変えていくよ
Like a song, like a miracle, thoughts change everything,
きっと きっと 驚くくらい
surely, surely, enough to amaze you.
I’m a dreamer 潜むパワー
I'm a dreamer, a hidden power,
まだ見ぬ世界
a world yet unseen,
そこで何が待っていても
no matter what awaits there,
もしも理想とちがっても 恐れはしない
even if it differs from my ideals, I won't be afraid.
鳥たちは風にのり旅をしてゆく 今日から明日へと
Birds ride on the wind and journey on from today into tomorrow.
伝えたいな さけびたいな
I want to tell it, I want to shout it out,
この世に一つだけの存在である私
as the one and only existence in this world,
祈るように 星のように 小さな光だけど何時かは
praying like a star, a small light that someday...
もっと もっと つよく なり たい
wants to become stronger, stronger still.
もっとわ もっと…
Even more... even more...
もっと強くなりたい
I want to become even stronger,
I want to become even stronger.
限界のない 可能性がここにある
A limitless potential is right here,
この手に… It's gonna be your world
in my hands... It's gonna be your world.
見つけたいな かなえたいな
I want to find it, I want to fulfill it,
信じるそれだけで 越えられないものはない
just by believing, there's nothing that cannot be overcome.
歌うように 奇跡のように
As if singing, like a miracle,
想いが全てを変えてゆくよ
"thoughts" are going to change everything.
きっと きっと
Surely, surely,
驚くくらい
enough to surprise you.
というわけで プラチナでした！ありがとうございました！
And that was "Platinum"! Thank you very much!
はあ、ちょっと、あの、久しぶりのライブなのでちょっぴり緊張したけれども、あの、頑張って歌えたなって思います。
I feel like I managed to sing my best, even though I was a bit nervous since it's been a while.
はい。でもね、ここからは、実は一人じゃないんです！
Yes. But you know, from here on... actually, I'm not alone!
いろんな人がゲストに来てくれるって聞いてるんだけど、次の曲は誰が来てくれるのかなぁ？
I heard various people are coming as guests, but I wonder who's coming for the next song?
え？この声は？この声は誰？
Eh? Whose voice is this? Whose voice is that?
おめでとーー！お誕生日おめでとーー！おめでとーー！
Happy birthday! Happy birthday! Happy birthday!
ありがとう！嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm so happy!
すごい！おっきいケーキだね！
Amazing! That's a huge cake!
持ってきました！おたんじょうびおめでとう！
We brought it! Happy birthday!
すごい！え、こんな美味しそうなケーキ、みんなで食べるために持ってきたんでしょ？
Incredible! You brought such a delicious-looking cake so we could all eat it together, right?
え？何そのテンション？
Eh? What's with that reaction?
え、そうなんだけど…みおちゃんのためだからね！
Eh, well it is... it's for Mio-chan!
いや、今日は簡単には食べられません！食べられません！
No, today you won't be able to eat it easily! You can't eat it!
ここで白上クイズぅぅうう！
Here is the Shirakami Quiz!
ちょっと待って！うち誕生日なのに！
Wait a minute! It's my birthday!
なんかすごい検問がない？なんで？
Why is there such a strict checkpoint? Why?!
このね、白上からのクイズに答えられたら…食べる動機ができます！
If you can answer this quiz from Shirakami... you earn the right to eat it!
え、待って白上、え、いつもうちがめちゃぶりしてること怒ってる？めちゃぶり怒ってないよ？怒ってない！
Eh, wait, Shirakami... wait, are you mad at me for all those unreasonable requests I always make? I'm not mad! I'm not mad!
え、そういうことじゃない？え、なんだ恨み辛みがあるのか？はっきり言え！
Eh, that's not it? Then what, do you have grudges? Speak clearly!
ないや！ないや！ないのかよ！
No way! No way! You don't?!
やがらせだよ！お誕生日の嫌がらせ！
It's harassment! Birthday harassment!
クイズに答えられたら食べれます！あ、もし答えられたらね、答えられなかった場合は…あやめちゃんが食べます！
If you answer the quiz, you can eat! Ah, if you can answer it, but if you can't... Ayame-chan will eat it!
よかったね！よがたね！
Yay! Good for you!
じゃあさ、じゃあさ、用のフォークを持ってくるなり…あ、じゃあ、用の食べるフォークを召喚します！
Then, um... I'll summon a fork to eat it with!
はっ！てん！
Ha! Ten!
よし！ついた！え、答えられたらあやめちゃんがアーンしてくれるそうなのでね！
Alright! I got it! Eh, if I answer correctly, Ayame-chan will feed me "ah"!
よがアーンしちゃいますよ！
Yoca will feed you!
わ、アーンて食べたいな！あやめちゃん、一個取っちゃっていい？あ、いいですか？
Wow, I want to be fed "ah"! Ayame-chan, can I take one? Ah, is that okay?
よーよし、ちょっとこちら失礼させていただきますよ。
Yo-yoshi, excuse me for a moment here.
おいしょ！お、あ、取れた！あ、いただけた！はい！
Heave-ho! Oh, ah, got it! Ah, I got it! Yes!
これで食べれるということで！ねえ、欲しい？欲しいか？これ食べたいか？食べたいか？
With this, I can eat! Hey, do you want it? Do you want it? Do you want to eat this? Do you want to eat it?
ケーキの、ケーキの匂いを確かめてやるんだ！ケーキの良い香りをちょっと…
I'm gonna check the cake's scent! Let's check the nice aroma of the cake...
かせ、かせ！いい香りを、かふふふふ！ねえ、こちら、クイズ正解したらね、よがアーンしてあげますので！
Smell it, smell it! The nice aroma, sniff sniff! Hey, if you answer the quiz correctly, Yoca will feed you "ah"!
カロリーの塊、カロリー爆弾を、お届けしますよ！よろしいですか？
A lump of calories, a calorie bomb, is what I'm delivering! Is that okay?
よろしいです！はいじゃあいきます！なんだろ？クイズです！ででーん！
That's fine! Alright, here we go! What could it be? It's a quiz! Tada!
ええと、7月の24日、25日どっちだった？日曜日…毎週日曜日に公開されてるホログラからの、問題です！
Um, July 24th or 25th, which one was it? Sunday... It's a question from Hologra, which is released every Sunday!
ほう、今回はされた
Oh, this time it was...
ホロぐらの話？
A Hologra story?
え、内容はですね、遅れた七夕でした！
Um, the content was a belated Tanabata!
あー！
Ah!
七夕会、遅れた七夕会ありましたね。
There was a Tanabata party, a belated Tanabata party.
それ見てよ！
Look at that!
本当に？みんな見た？
Really? Did everyone see it?
じゃあそのホロぐら内で一番最後に喋った白髪のセリフは何だ？
Then what was the white-haired girl's last line in that Hologra?
え？
Eh?
なんだっけ、なんだっけ、なんだっけ？
What was it, what was it, what was it?
あ、なんか、来年も会おうねみたいな感じだったっけ？
Ah, was it something like "Let's meet again next year"?
あれ？それでいいですか？
Huh? Is that good?
はい？ナレーションですか？
Huh? Is it narration?
フェイントだった？いいですか？
Was it a feint? Is that okay?
え、ちょ、え、え、ファ、ヒ、ヒ、ヒント、ヒント、ヒント！ヒントとは何に対するのツッコミでした！
Eh, wait, a hint, hint, hint! The hint was a tsukkomi to something!
えー、じゃあ違うじゃん！
Eh, then that's wrong!
えー！ツッコミでした。さて。
Eh! It was a tsukkomi. Now then.
なんだけな。いや、見た、これ見た、これ見た、これだよ！
What was it? No, I saw this, I saw this, this is it!
10, 9, 8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1
なんか短冊に対しての、なんか、願いのよ、ような気がしたけど。
It felt like some kind of wish regarding the tanzaku, though.
ああ、頼んだぞ！
Ah, I left it to you!
えと、この願い事でいいんかい！みたいなやつ？
Like, "Is this wish really okay?!" or something?
フセカ！
You've got to be kidding me!
違うじゃん！
That's wrong!
なんて！なんて！なんてさ！
What, what, what is it!
うちのケーキ！
Our cake!
ということでね、世界なんで、ホールケーキ食べたいじゃお…
So, since it's the world, we want to eat a whole cake, so...
いただきます！
Let's eat!
いただきまーす！
Bon appétit!
おいしかったな！
That was delicious!
ホールケーキだからね！
Because it's a whole cake!
いや、でっかいケーキは格別だね！
Man, a huge cake is extra special!
もう、うちもケーキ食べたかったよ、これは！
Man, I wanted to eat cake too, honestly!
残りのケーキはね、短髪が食べます！
The remaining cake will be eaten by Tanzaku!
えっ？どういうこと？どういうこと？どういうこと？えっ？ちょっと、ちょっと、
Eh? What do you mean? What do you mean? What do you mean? Eh? Wait, wait...
一瞬ケーキがちっちゃくなっていく！
For a second, the cake is getting smaller!
食べちゃった！短冊の中に入っちゃった！
She ate it! It went inside the tanzaku!
いや、腹八分目もしましたし、ライブでもしますか？
Well, we're 80% full, so shall we do a live performance?
なんたこれ！なんだこの茶番は！
What is this! What kind of farce is this!
いや、ケーキ1個しか食べれないよ！
I mean, we can only eat one cake!
お腹すいた！
I'm hungry!
ちゃんと食後の運動と、ちゃんと食後の運動に、せっかくライブ来てくれたんだから二人ともね、踊ってくれるよね？
Proper post-meal exercise... since you two came to the live concert, you'll dance with me, right?
うん！やった！踊りましょう！
Yeah! Yay! Let's dance!
じゃあ、立ち位置につこうか。いや、わかる？この3人と言ったら何ですか？
Then let's take our positions. Wait, do you know? What do these three people represent?
じゃあ、いきますよ！あの曲と言えば、せーの！百花繚乱花吹雪！
Then, here we go! Speaking of that song, ready, go! Hyakka Ryouran Hanafubuki!
色付く想いは切な百花繚乱花吹雪
Colored feelings are a poignant, hundred-flower riot of falling cherry blossoms.
パッと咲いて散った花は終わりにを告げてくその時を待てど暮らせど言葉は進まず
Flowers that bloomed brilliantly and fell announced their end, waiting and living in vain as words wouldn't advance.
ちょっと触れて知った胸の内の温かさを初めてのこの気持ちだけ抱きしめていたい
Wanting to hold tight to this first feeling of warmth in my chest I learned by touching just a little.
約束交わした約束は本物だって信じてる
I believe the promise we exchanged is real.
色はにほへとのかなに魅せられた少女たちあはらりあはらりあはらり落ちる花と舞い踊れ
Maiden girls fascinated by "Iro ha ni ho he to", ah, fluttering, falling gently with the falling flowers, dance away!
若さゆえとしても重いこと飲み込んでみた誰もみな焦がれる現世の断りよ
Swallowing heavy things even in our youth, everyone yearns for this world's logic.
色付く想いは切な百花繚乱花吹雪
Colored feelings are a poignant, hundred-flower riot of falling cherry blossoms.
ふっと息消した夜を灯す月明かりに曖昧な心が揺れて声は響く
The moonlight illuminating the night where breath vanished makes an ambiguous heart sway, and voices echo.
もっと触れたくって夢をなぞる指先さえいつの日か果てた形を忘れかけてた
Wanting to touch more, even tracing dreams with fingertips, I had begun to forget the shape that once ended someday.
浮世の波にたゆらう時歌かたの夢は弾けてく
When swaying in the waves of the floating world, fleeting dreams burst open.
ういのおくやさらにあれる
Failing green mountains...
色づく想いは順情
Feelings that color are pure passion,
そののらりくらり ここから揺らめき歌い続けるが
drifting leisurely, flickering from here, we continue to sing.
朝日夢見しと想い 踏み込むこの世界は
Dreaming of the morning sun, stepping into this world,
誰もみな焦がれる 現世の理よ
everyone yearns for it—the logic of this mortal world.
色づく想いは切な 百花繚乱 花吹雪
Feelings that color are fleeting, a hundred flowers blooming.
泉が数えて ごこごにさおいでおいで
Counting the springs, come on over here,
暁交わした約束は
The promise exchanged at dawn
本物だってきっと信じてる
is the real deal, I'm sure of it.
いろはにほへと の 花 に 魅せられ た 少女 たち
Girls captivated by the flowers of "Iroha ni hoheto",
あぁ はらり はらり はらり 落ちる 花弁 と 舞い 踊れ
Ah, fluttering down, dance and spin with falling petals.
ろかよたれそ でも 想い 心も跳ね込めてみた
Even so, I tried putting my feelings and words into it.
誰もみな焦がれる 現世の理よ
Everyone yearns for it—the logic of this mortal world.
色づく想いは切な 百花繚乱 花吹雪
Feelings that color are fleeting, a hundred flowers blooming.
風になる 乙女の順情 乙女の順情 さきほこれ
Turning into the wind, maidens' pure passion—bloom in full glory!
お疲れ様でした！踊ったねー！
Good job everyone! We danced so much!
いやーこちらこそ！限界までごちそうになっちゃって
Thank you so much! We're stuffed to the limit!
お腹いっぱいだね お腹いっぱいになりました
We're so full! My tummy is totally full.
そっか それならよかったんだが ごちそうさまでした！
Is that so? Well, I'm glad. Thanks for the meal!
うち曲は「百花繚乱花吹雪」を越えて3人で踊るのめっちゃ好きなの
I really love dancing to "Hyakkaryouran" with us three!
わかる 楽しい！そうなんだよー
I know, it's so fun! Yeah, exactly.
もう一生懸命覚えたしさ 今でも覚えているしさと
We worked so hard to learn it, and we still remember it.
そう 振り付けが合うときとかすごい気持ちいいしさ おめでとう！ありがとう！
Yeah, when choreography matches it feels amazing. Happy birthday!
ま ちょっとケーキは食い切られてしまったけれども
Well, the cake got completely eaten up though,
また今度また今度別でお祝いし そうそう！うれしいから！やった！
We'll celebrate separately next time! Yeah, we're so happy!
劇パーティしや 撃破じゃなくて パーティしようね ね
Let's have a party! Not defeat, let's have a party, right?
ということでね 我々は帰るか
So with that, should we head back?
え、帰っちゃうの？ 画面裏で見てるから大丈夫
Eh, you're leaving? We're watching from behind the screen so it's fine.
もう賑やかにしてくれても全然いいから あ、後ろでずっとこうやってこうやって
You can make all the noise you want. Ah, just doing this...
ありがとう ありがとう あ、そうだ,今日ね Mioのラッキーポットを押せば聞いてたんだ
Thank you. Oh right, today if you press Mio's Lucky Spot...
ラッキーポット？ ラッキーポット海らしいよ
Lucky Spot? Apparently the Lucky Spot is the ocean.
海？ 海？ 夏だしか、確かに
The ocean? It's summer, so true.
海がすごい穴場らしいです へえ、なんかちょっと海っていう
Apparently the ocean is a great hidden spot. Eh, like heading to...
うちゆけほらびとか見ていたいな あ、いいね！いいね！そんなことできるのかなあ
I'd love to go on an hot spring trip. Ah, that'd be nice!
夏だしくみたいね やりたいけどね うん
Since it's summer, you know. We'd love to, yeah.
とりあえずね 我々は ちょっとさっきに お祝いと乾杯したぜ おめでとうね ありがとうね バイバイ バイバイ
Anyway, we celebrated and made a toast earlier! Happy birthday!
ラッキーポット海だって。え、でも他のメンバーもいるかもしれないから、ちょっと海いってみようかな。
Lucky Spot is the ocean... Maybe I should go check it out.
あーーすごい星空！ちょっとね、あの、お祝いなので海行きたいなって思って夏だし海に来ちゃいました！
Ah, what a starry sky! Since it's a celebration, I wanted to go to the ocean!
あれ？あれあれ？お、澪ちゃん？どうしよう。え、わ、忘れもの？ここ、ここスタジオじゃないよ？
Huh? What's this? Oh, Mio-chan? What do we do? Is this the studio?
あれ、なんか、あれ？なんでここ海なのここ？
Huh, wait... why is it the ocean here?
あ、夏だか、うちが来たいなって思って、夏、あ、そうなんだよワープしてきちゃったんだよ
Since it's summer I wanted to come here, so we warped right over!
だから、なんかね、ちょっと、みおちゃんとまだ歌いたかったなと思って歩いてたらね、なんか海に着いちゃったんだね。
I wanted to sing with Mio a bit more and ended up at the ocean.
うちのことを思いながら歩いてたら、いつの間にかきちゃった？うん、海に着いてました。
You were walking thinking of us and ended up here? Yeah!
それって 手手ってこと？ ありがとう！やったー！
Does that mean hand-in-hand? Thank you! Yay!
あれ？
Huh?
この曲… なんか聴く… なんか聴いたことある？
This song... It sounds... Have you heard it before?
うん、なんだろ？
Yeah, I wonder what it is?
え？
Eh?
じゃあこの曲、二人で歌おうか？
Well then, shall we sing this song together?
歌おうか！
Let's sing it!
おお！
Oh!
ええ、二人で歌うの初めて！楽しみだなあ！
Yay, it's our first time singing together! I'm so excited!
あの日見渡した渚を 今も思い出すんだ
I still remember the shore we looked out at that day.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
The words carved in the sand, and the back of your figure.
寄り添う波が足元を よぎり何かをさらう
The cuddling waves brush past my feet and sweep something away.
夕凪の中 日暮れだけが通り過ぎていく
In the evening calm, only twilight passes us by.
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched the fireworks bloom in a flash of light.
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely, a summer that hasn't ended yet...
曖昧な心を透過して繋いだ この夜が続いて欲しかった
connecting our uncertain hearts through it, I wanted this night to go on.
あと何回君と同じ 花火を見られるかなって
I wonder how many more times I can see fireworks with you.
笑う顔に何ができるだろうか
What can I do to bring a smile to your face?
傷付くこと喜ぶこと 繰り返す波と情動焦燥 最終列車の音
Hurt and joy, repeating waves, impatience, and the last train's sound.
何度でも言葉にして 君を呼ぶよ 波間を選び もう一度
No matter how many times, I'll call you by name, choosing the gaps between waves, once more.
もう二度と悲しまずに 済むように
So we never have to be sad again.
はっと息をのめば 消えちゃいそうな光が
If I catch my breath, a light that might fade away...
きっとまだ胸に住んでいた
was surely still dwelling in my chest.
手を伸ばせば触れた あったかい未来は ひそかにふたりを見ていた
The warm future we touched when we reached out was secretly watching over us.
パッと花火が 夜に咲いた
Fireworks bloomed in the night.
夜に咲いた
Bloomed in the night,
静かに消えた 静かに消えた
and quietly faded away, quietly faded away.
離さないで もう少しだけ
Don't let go, just a little longer,
もう少しだけ もう少しだけ このままで
just a little longer, just a little longer, let's stay like this.
あの日見渡した渚を 今も思い出すんだ
I still remember the shore we looked out at that day.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
The words carved in the sand, and the back of your figure.
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched the fireworks bloom in a flash of light.
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely, a summer that hasn't ended yet...
曖昧な心を透過して繋いだ この夜が続いて欲しかった
connecting our uncertain hearts through it, I wanted this night to go on.
ラララ…
La la la...
花火や！
Fireworks!
すごい！めちゃ花火上がってる！綺麗だね！
Amazing! So many fireworks are going off! It's so pretty!
ね、綺麗！すごい！
Right, so pretty! Amazing!
あ、忘れとった！忘れとった！あぶない！
Oh, I forgot! I forgot! Oh, close one!
いやー、なんか二人で歌うの初めてだったけどさ
Man, it was our first time singing together...
あー すごい良かったよ！お疲れ！
Ah, that was amazing! Good job!
え、ちょっと、曲がちょっと、緊張しちゃった。
U-Um, the song made me a little nervous.
あ、きちゃった？
Ah, it got to you?
いいね、曲が夏らしい、すごい。
It was nice, very summery.
あやめちゃんと歌えてうれしかった。
I was so happy to sing with Ayame-chan.
やあ、ありがと、うれしい！
Yay, thank you, I'm so happy!
また一緒に歌いたいな。
I want to sing together again.
うん、これからもまた歌おうね。
Yeah, let's keep singing together.
あ、大丈夫？おめでとう！
Ah, are you okay? Congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとうね。
Thank you.
気をつけて帰るんだよ。
Be careful on your way home, okay?
こんなとこまで来ちゃったけど、一人でちょっと頑張って帰ろう。
We came all the way out here, so I'll try my best to walk back alone.
あーなんかちょっと心配になってきちゃった。大丈夫？
Ah... I'm starting to get a little worried. Are you okay?
大丈夫、水上ボートで帰るから。水上ボートあるで。
It's fine, I'm going back on a water boat. There's water boats.
バイバイン！気をつけてね、みおちゃん、気をつけてね！
Bye-bye! Be careful, Mio-chan, be careful!
はぁ、お家帰っちゃったな。
Haah, she went home...
すごい花火だな。きれい。
Such amazing fireworks. So pretty.
あ！みおしゃ！あ！きらー！
Ah! Mio-sha! Ah, killer!
みおしゃ！起きてー！
Mio-sha! Wake up!
なんかうるさい。
You guys are so loud.
起きて起きて起きて起きて起きて起きて！
Wake up, wake up, wake up, wake up!
え、起きた？
Huh, did you wake up?
起きた？
You're awake?
起きたけどなになになになになに？おい！
I'm awake, but what, what, what, what is this?! Hey!
なになになになになに？お前は何なの？おい！
What, what, what, what are you guys doing?! Hey!
みんなどうしたの？何でこんなとこにいるの？
Why is everyone here? Why are you in a place like this?
え？知らん。
Eh? Dunno.
なんかみおちゃんが海に落ちてたからさ、そうだよ！拾ったんだよ！拾ってあげたの！
Well, Mio-chan fell into the ocean, so yeah! We picked you up! We picked you up!
そう、ありがとう。
Oh, thank you.
生きてた。
You were alive.
よかった、よかったよ、生きててよかった。生きててよかったよ、本当によかったね。
I'm so glad, I'm so glad you're alive. I'm so glad you're alive.
なんか、なんでここにいたの？
Wait, why were you here?
いや、なんか昨日、え？なんか花火を見てて、あ、やめと一緒に歌ってよーな気がするの。
Well, yesterday, um? I was watching fireworks, and I feel like I was singing together with Ayame.
そのあと気を失って海に漂っててだって！
And then you passed out and drifted in the ocean, they say!
本当に？！
Really?!
そういうこと！？
Is that what happened?!
やばいねそれ、なんかバカされたような気持ちだよ。
That's crazy, I feel like I got tricked or something.
あー、そう。プレゼントを持ってきたの！プレゼント！？
Ah, right. We brought a present! A present?!
ああ、いいね！じゃあじゃあ！
Ah, nice! Then, then!
お！じゃじゃーん！スイカじゃん！スイカじゃん！
Tada! It's a watermelon! It's a watermelon!
スイカ！スイカ！スイカ！スイカ！スイカ！スイカ！スイカ！スイカ！
Watermelon! Watermelon! Watermelon!
コロネを差し置いてめちゃめちゃ喜んでんじゃん。
You're way more excited than Korone.
確かに！スイカだもんね、スイカ！
True! It's a watermelon, watermelon!
え、みんな食べる？食べたーい！
Eh, does everyone want to eat? I want to eat!
せっかくだからさ、スイカ割りとかしない？夏の思い出に。
Since we have the chance, shouldn't we do watermelon splitting? For summer memories.
いいね！やろう、やろう！
Sounds good! Let's do it!
面白い！誰が割る？え？あ…
That's fun! Who's going to split it? Eh? Ah...
それはまあ、ちょっと尺が、ちょっと巻き気味で行かなきゃいけない、尺が？
Well, that's... we need to keep things a bit brief, time-wise... time?
あらちょっと、そうだな、じゃあ、
Oh my, is that so, then,
4人で同時に、もう、同時に？！
all four of us at the same time? At the same time?!
同時に！うわ！なんだこれ！？
At the same time! Whoa, what is this?!
嘘のいい棒が！こんなところに棒が！
A fake good stick! There's a stick in a place like this!
じゃあね、これ4人で目隠しをして、
So, the four of us will put on blindfolds,
誤解、回ったと思ったらスイカ割りにいこう。5回回るの？うん。
and once we think we've spun around 5 times, let's go for the watermelon. Spin 5 times? Yeah.
オッケー！じゃあちょっと離れよう。あ、ちょっとじゃあリハーサルやろうか、リハーサル。
Okay! Then let's step back a bit. Ah, let's do a rehearsal first, a rehearsal.
わ、なんだ！目が！
Woah, what! My eyes!
目が！見えない！見えない！見えない！見える！
My eyes! I can't see! I can't see! I can't see! I can see!
コロネ、お前何ずらしてんだよ！ずるいな！これでいいの。
Korone, what are you shifting your blindfold for?! So sneaky! This is fine.
よいしょ。あー、よかったよかった。
Heave-ho. Ah, good, good.
そろえ！そうじゃねえよ！ずらしとったでさ。あ、あたしかが。
Soroe! That's not it! You were shifting it. Ah, I guess.
じゃあちょっと、1回回らずにやってみようか。スイカ割れるかどうか。よーい、スタート！リハーサル！
Then let's try it once without spinning. See if we can split the watermelon. Ready, start! Rehearsal!
割れてた！
It split!
割れてる割れてる！嘘でしょ！？
It's split, it's split! No way?!
え、嘘でしょ？！
Eh, no way?!
やばい！
Oh no!
早い早い早い！
Too fast, too fast!
やばい、壊れている、壊れている！
Oh no, it's broken, it's broken!
え、なんかやばかったって、今。
Eh, that was crazy just now.
待って待って、割れてるよ。割れてるよ！
Wait, wait, it's split. It's split!
割れてる、あ、割れてるっぽい。
Split, ah, looks like it's split.
え、割れてるの？
Eh, it's split?
あ、割れてますね。
Ah, it is split.
割れとるやないかい！
Of course it is!
じゃあちょっと、もう1回、じゃあ本番ということで。
Then let's do it one more time as the actual round.
わかった。じゃあ、
Understood. Then,
今度はさっきのバキって爆発するの！なんかトーマスみたいに来たよ。
This time, the cracking explosion from earlier! It came like Thomas or something.
走り回ってたよね。なんだあれは。なんで割れたんだろ？
You were running around. What was that? Why did it split?
目隠ししてるからわかんないんだよ。
We're wearing blindfolds so we don't know.
じゃあ、ちょっとじゃあみんなスイカから若干離れた状態でいきますよ。
Okay, then let's start with everyone slightly away from the watermelon.
じゃあ5回回って。
Spin around 5 times.
オッケー。5回回ったなと思ったらスタートだからね。はい、目瞑って。行きますよ。
Okay. When you think you've spun 5 times, that's the start. Okay, close your eyes. Here we go.
はーい！スタート！
Ready! Start!
1、2、3、4、5！
1, 2, 3, 4, 5!
やべえ、どっちが前？！
Oh no, which way is front?!
スイカだー！
Watermelon!
わー！
Wah!
割れたー！
It split!
あれ？ すごくない？
Huh? Isn't that amazing?
あれ待って。大体大丈夫？
Wait a minute. Is everyone okay?
大丈夫？
You okay?
全然進んでないじゃん！
You guys haven't made any progress!
なんかだっておわったらお迎えそっちでスバルどこにいたっけよ
I mean, once it's over, Subaru, where were you even waiting?
じゃあどうしよう。食べてくれる？みんなで。
So what should we do? Will you eat it together with everyone?
まぁたださ、このスイカ ちょっとね、汚れたりとかもしたし
Well, but, this watermelon got a bit dirty and stuff,
一回さ、誕生日のケーキもあるからさ
and since there's also a birthday cake,
事務所に帰ってさ、休憩しながら食べよん？
let's go back to the office and eat it while taking a break, right?
いいねー！
Sounds good!
じゃあ一旦事務所に戻っちゃお！
Let's head back to the office for now!
おっしゃー！
Let's go!
みんな、集まれー！
Everyone, gather around!
スイカ！スイカ！スイカ！スイカ！ケーキもケーキも！
Watermelon! Watermelon! Watermelon! And cake too!
スイカ！
Watermelon!
あれ？
Huh?
なんかある。なんかゴミ落ちてんだけど。
There's something here. Some trash dropped on the floor.
捨てとけよ、ゴミ。
Throw it away then, trash.
本当だよ！ゴミでっけぇ。
That's right! It's huge.
ゴミでっけぇ！
It's huge!
ゴミでっかくない？
Isn't it huge?
「アイドルらしく可愛く歌えないと、ケーキとスイカはお預けです」って書いてある。
It says, "If you can't sing cute and idol-like, the cake and watermelon are on hold."
殺されたんじゃ！
We're doomed!
誰だいったよ！
Who said that?!
もう無理だ！
No way!
誰だいったよ！
Who said that?!
諦めのいいよ！
Give up already!
もう無理だ！
No way!
無理じゃんそんなの！
That's impossible!
いやでも可愛く歌えないと、だから可愛く歌えばいいじゃん！
But if we can't sing cute, then we just need to sing cute!
本当？
Really?
適当言ってんじゃねえよ！
Don't just say whatever!
ケーキ返してください！
Please give back the cake!
ケーキ返してください！スイカスイカスイカスイカ！
Please give back the cake! Watermelon watermelon watermelon!
返ってこないということは別に入って感じですね、やっぱですね。
Not getting it back means it's whatever, I suppose.
これは可愛い判定に引っかからないね。
This isn't passing the cute judgment.
でしょ！
Right!
はい、というわけでじゃあちょっと可愛い衣装から、衣装からいこうか。
Right, so let's start with cute outfits!
なるほど。
I see.
うん、うちらの可愛い衣装わかるよね？
Yeah, you know our cute outfits, right?
もちろん！
Of course!
じゃあちょっと着替えちゃおうかな。おきみのー！
Then let's go change. Okimino—!
せーの、じゃーん！
Ready, set, ta-da!
可愛い！可愛い！可愛いねー！
Cute! Cute! So cute!
合格でいいでしょ！
Passing is fine, right?
もう合格！合格！
Already passed! Passed!
合格！合格！合格！合格！合格！合格！合格は？
Pass! Pass! Pass! Pass! Pass! Pass! What about pass?
合格は？
What about pass?
ああ、だめだって。
Ah, no good.
おい！
Hey!
なんでだよ！なんでだよ！
Why?! Why?!
ちゃんとケーキ出てこいよ、こんなの！
Bring out the cake properly for this!
食べたかったら食べなきゃいけないんだよ。
If you want to eat it, you gotta eat it.
そっか。その歌を歌わなきゃいけないんだ。
I see. We have to sing that song.
ちょっとさ、じゃあ4人で歌う曲考えたいんだけどさ。
So, I want to think of a song for the four of us to sing.
え、ここで歌うの？
Eh, we're singing it here?
いや、もうここにまあ、ジャッジする人がいるんだよ。
Well, there's someone here to judge.
ここ！？
Here?!
なんかダンボールとかあるよ。
There's some cardboard boxes and stuff.
本当だよ。せめてもうちょっと片付ければ。
Really. At least clean up a bit more.
ほら、なんか五机、ジェット机みたいなあるよ。
Look, there's some desk, like a jet desk.
勝手に買っちゃう。
Buying things on their own.
ああ、まじ殺される！
Ah, we're seriously gonna get killed!
勝手に買ってきたのか。
They bought it on their own?
そうだ。みんなさ、リスナーさんも知ってるし、多分4人とも知ってるかなって思う曲があるんだけどさ。
That's right. Everyone, the listeners know it, and I think all four of us know it too.
なに？
What?
おちゃめ機能っていうんだけど。
It's called "Ochame Kinou".
ああ！
Ah!
知ってるー！みんなで歌わせてる。歌った歌った。
I know it! Everyone sings it. Sung it, sung it.
それちょっと可愛いし、ちょっと4人で歌ってみない？
That's pretty cute, why don't the four of us try singing it?
いいね！いいね！
Sounds good! Sounds good!
てててれってってってってって... まだまだまだまだ！
Te-te-te-re-te-te-te... Not yet, not yet!
ちゃんとBGMあると思うからね。あ、アカペラだった。よかった。
There should be BGM, right? Ah, it was acapella. Good thing.
よかったー！
Great!
それでは、おちゃめ機能をいってみよう！
Well then, let's try "Ochame Kinou"!
で、ポーズ！ポーズ！
And pose! Pose!
いつでも I love you. 君に take kiss me.
I love you always. You take kiss me.
忘れないから 僕の大事なメモリー
I cannot forget this precious memory of mine.
どら焼きは主食になれない
If dorayaki cannot become my main diet,
ならば上書きしちゃえば
I'll just have to overwrite it
僕の思い通り
my way.
ずっとそばで見てるよ
I'm always watching by your side,
バックアップは任せて
so leave the backup to me.
左から右へと
From left to right...
いつでも I love you.
I will always "I love you,"
君に Take kiss me.
when you "Take kiss me."
忘れられないから
I will never forget that
僕の大切なメモリー
because it's my precious memory.
どら焼きは主食になれない
Dorayaki cannot be a staple food,
ならば上書きしちゃえば僕の思い通り
so if I just overwrite it, it's just as I want!
夢からピピピ 覚めないで
Don't wake up from my dream with a pipipi,
ぬくもり 逃げないで
don't let the warmth escape,
まだ朝は たっぷりあるから
morning is still full of time,
あと5分待ってって
so wait 5 minutes more!
100年後続くなら約束圧縮して
If it lasts 100 years, let's compress our promise!
間違えたメールから 勘違いのテキパキ
From a wrong email to a misunderstood text,
ストローのくわえ方 少しは違うでしょ？
aren't the ways we hold our straws slightly different?
見てみぬふりされた 世界が爆発しちゃう！
If everyone turns a blind eye, the world will explode!
調子にのりだす でもすぐにへこみだす
I get carried away, but then immediately get down,
華麗な暴走 誰か止めてくれますかべいびー
who will stop my magnificent rampage for me, baby?
ぶつかればまた新しい知識発掘で
When I bump into something, I discover new knowledge,
でも力尽きてしまえばそこまで Oh my god !
but if I run out of stamina, that's it, oh my god!
いつでも I love you.
I will always "I love you,"
君に Take kiss me.
when you "Take kiss me."
お星様に願い事 叶えてくれますか
Will the stars grant my wishes for me?
地球の裏側まで 私をはこんで
Carry me to the other side of the Earth,
一番綺麗な花を 探しに行った
and let's go search for the most beautiful flower.
まだ君の熱い想いは想いは
Your burning passion is still,
頬に伝う涙 水色は胸に包んで
tears on cheeks, wrapped in our hearts.
届けるよ空に Are you ready ?
I'll deliver it to the sky, are you ready?
いつでも I love you. 君に Take kiss me.
I will always "I love you," when you "Take kiss me."
お星様に願い事 叶えてくれますか
Will the stars grant my wishes for me?
地球の裏側まで 私をはこんで
Carry me to the other side of the Earth,
一番綺麗な花を 探しに行った
and let's go search for the most beautiful flower.
まだ君の熱い想いは想いは
Your burning passion is still,
頬に伝う涙 水色は胸に包んで
tears on cheeks, wrapped in our hearts.
届けるよ空に おもいっ切り！
I'll deliver it to the sky with all my might!
いつでも I love you.
I will always "I love you,"
君に Take kiss me.
when you "Take kiss me."
忘れられないから 僕の大切なメモリー
I will never forget that because it's my precious memory.
どら焼きは主食になれない
Dorayaki cannot be a staple food,
ならば上書きしちゃえば 僕の思い通り
so if I just overwrite it, it's just as I want!
まだ君の熱い想いは想いは
Your burning passion is still,
頬に伝う涙
tears on cheeks,
胸に包んで 届けるよ 空に
wrapped in our hearts, delivered to the sky!
やほー！
Yahoo!
どうかな、かわいいか？
What do you think, is it cute?
かわいいよ！もっと一可愛いよ！
So cute! Even more cute!
天才も吸い込む可愛さだからね！
Because it's a cuteness that sucks in even geniuses!
やめないで包まれて
Don't stop, get enveloped!
おっ！そろそろ始まるんじゃね？
Oh! Is it about to start?
まじか！ラストスパート行くぞ！
Seriously! Let's go for the final sprint!
いつでも I love you. 君に Take kiss me.
I will always "I love you," when you "Take kiss me."
お星様に願い事 叶えてくれますか
Will the stars grant my wishes for me?
地球の裏側まで 私をはこんで
Carry me to the other side of the Earth,
一番綺麗な花を 探しに行った
and let's go search for the most beautiful flower.
まだ君の熱い想いは想いは
Your burning passion is still,
頬に伝う涙
tears on cheeks,
水色は胸に包んで 届けるよ 空に
wrapped in our hearts, delivered to the sky!
いつでも I love you. 君に Take kiss me.
I will always "I love you," when you "Take kiss me."
忘れられないから 僕の大切なメモリー
I will never forget that because it's my precious memory.
どら焼きは主食になれない
Dorayaki cannot be a staple food,
ならば上書きしちゃえば 僕の思い通り
so if I just overwrite it, it's just as I want!
夢からピピピ 覚めないで
Don't wake up from my dream with a pipipi,
ぬくもり逃げないで まだ朝はたっぷりあるから
don't let the warmth escape, morning is still full of time,
あと5分...
so wait 5 minutes...
100年後続くなら 約束圧縮して！
If it lasts 100 years, let's compress our promise!
ケーキだー！ケーキだ！
It's a cake! It's a cake!
ケーキの ケーキの おめでとう！
Cake, cake, congratulations!
おめでとー！
Congratulations!
え、ちょっと、追いかける？
Hey, wait, should we chase it?
そうだね！おいかけよ！
That's right! Let's chase it!
待ってー！
Wait up!
おろそう、いなかったね
We couldn't catch it, right?
よかったー！
Thank goodness!
結構全力でおっかけたんだけど
We chased it with all our might though!
ねー！
Yeah!
ほんで早かった
And it was so fast!
やっぱりね、足は違う
As expected, legs are different.
それでも追いつかなかった
Even so, we couldn't catch up.
それでも猫は？
Even so, cats?
猫は無理だよ
Cats are impossible!
なんで猫にあきらめてんだよ
Why are you giving up on cats?
猫無理！
Cats are impossible!
やめられよ！
No way!
猫無理だよ
Cats are impossible!
そんなことないだろ！
That can't be true!
無理だ！
Impossible!
お前顔どうなってんだよ！
What's wrong with your face?!
絶望してた今、絶望してた
I was in despair just now, in despair!
自分がいぬじゃなかったということに絶望してた
I was in despair that I wasn't a dog!
猫もかわいいから大丈夫だよ
Cats are cute too, so it's fine!
本当に？
Really?
うん、かわいいかわいい
Yeah, cute, cute!
じゃあ猫で！
Then cat it is!
なんの話してんだよ
What are you even talking about?
あ、そういえばこの3人といえばさ
Oh, speaking of these three,
こないだやったさ、かしげめのオリジナル曲のさ、3人でもあるよね
we're also the three from the original song we did the other day!
そうだね！もうデシベル先生です
That's right! We're decibel teachers.
よろしくお願いします
Please treat us well.
お二人に歌詞を考えていただいたオリジナル楽曲
The original song where the two of you thought of the lyrics!
ちょっと今日発表しちゃおうかなって思っててさ
We were thinking of announcing it today—
えー！？
What?!
えっ？
Eh?
どういう発表なのそれわ
What kind of announcement is that?
そうだな！もう発表しちゃうの？
That's right! Should we announce it now?
そうなんだよ！
That's right!
だからちょっとね、今ちょっと歌っちゃうない？
So, shouldn't we sing it right now?
そんなノリで！？
What kind of mood is this?!
まあでもやっちゃいますかね、ここはね。
Well, we'll do it anyway, right? Here.
やっちゃいますか、猫先生。
Let's do it, Mio-sensei.
やっぱ先生方にうん頑張ってもらって。
Yeah, teachers, do your best.
僕たちにかかればね、いけますよ。このぐらいね。
If it's on us, we can do it! Around this much!
よろしくお願いします、先生方。
We're counting on you, teachers.
ま、だ、君誕生日だもんね。
Well, it's your birthday, after all.
あっ、そうなんですよう、誕生日なんです。
Oh, that's right, it's my birthday!
じゃあ、しょうがないからセンターどうぞ！
Well, it can't be helped, Center, go ahead!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ポジションはここ！ここに位置に就いて。
Here we go, position!
ポーズはこれ！
Pose is... here!
あれ？こっち？
Huh? Over here?
Over here?
みおしゃ？
Mio-sha?
間違えちゃった！あっちだよ！
Oh, I messed up! It's that way!
あっちだよ！
That way!
それでは、えー、オリジナル楽曲、
Then, uh, the original song,
さしみおです。
"Sashimio".
さしみお feat. スバおか
Sashimio feat. Subaoka
私の名前は大神ミオ！
My name is Ookami Mio!
今朝寝坊しちゃってさ、
I overslept this morning,
急いで髪の毛を直したよ。
So I had to fix my hair in a hurry!
実は実は今日ね、誕生日なの！
Today is actually my birthday,
だから今日はめいっぱい楽しく過ごしちゃうぞ！
So I'm gonna spend it happily, you see!
え、みおちゃん？
Wait, Mio-chan?
どうしたの？寝坊しちゃったの？
What happened? Did you oversleep?
そっか、大変だったね。
I see, that sounds rough.
よしよしよし！
Well, good job, good job!
あー、これからそんなことしたらめっだよ！
Hey, if you do stuff like that from now on, that's bad.
今日はうちにかえってウチとボンダリで食べよ。
Today you're going home to Onigiri and Onedari the cat.
え、お兄ちゃん？
Eh? Oni-chan?
なんでそんな男の子のことばっかり見るの？たまにはうちが君を見てほしい、みお。
Why are you only looking at other guys sometimes? I want you to look at me, Mio.
え、別に君のことが好きとか、そういうのじゃないけど、
Wait, it's not like I like other guys or anything.
うちも君も好きっていうか、君が好きなのか！
Wait, I like you too, I guess? I like you, I guess?
それってつまり、お刺身ってこと！？
That means... "Sashimi"?
もうすぐ始まるよ！
It's about to begin!
みおの放送待機待機待機！
Waiting for Mio's broadcast!
そろそろおおまちかね！
Get ready, everyone!
今日もいっぱい笑ってこ！
Today too, let's laugh a lot!
え、タイガー！タイガー！
Eh? A tiger? Tiger!
はえー！うわ、夢か！
So fast! Oh, it's a dream!
でもこんな時間じゃ、早く学校行かなくちゃ遅刻しちゃうよ！
But at this hour, if I don't hurry to school, I'll be late!
しかたがない。
Can't be helped.
パンだけ口に入れてダッシュだ！狼の体力なめんなよ！
Just put bread in my mouth and dash! Don't underestimate Ookami's stamina!
あー、もう今日1時間目なんだっけ？
Man, why is it already 1 hour later?
だったら何時から配信しようかな。
If so, what time should I start?
企画もそろそろ組みたいしな。
And the project is also falling apart, so...
こうやってパンだけ口に入れて走ってると、何か素敵な出会いがあるかもしれないよね。
Running with bread in my mouth like this might lead to a wonderful encounter.
よくあるシチュエーションだぞ。曲がり角でバッタリって感じで。
That's a classic situation! Like bumping into someone around a corner...
いやでもうちでも何か考えて走って、もしかしたらバッタリまして！
Yeah, but if I'm thinking about something while running... wait, bumping into someone?
いたたって、心臓痛っ！
It all happens in a heartbeat!
私の名前は大神ミオ！
My name is Ookami Mio!
今朝寝坊しちゃってさ、
I overslept this morning,
急いで髪の毛を直したよ。
So I had to fix my hair in a hurry!
実は実は今日ね、誕生日なの！
Today is actually my birthday,
だから今日はめいっぱい楽しく過ごしちゃうぞ！
So I'm gonna spend it happily, you see!
え、みおちゃん？
Wait, Mio-chan?
どうしたの？寝坊しちゃったの？
What happened? Did you oversleep?
そっか、大変だったね。
I see, that sounds rough.
よしよしよし！
Well, good job, good job!
あー、これからそんなことしたらめっだよ！
Hey, if you do stuff like that from now on, that's bad.
今日はうちにかえってウチとボンダリで食べよ。
Today you're going home to Onigiri and Onedari the cat.
え、お兄ちゃん？
Eh? Oni-chan?
なんでそんな男の子のことばっかり見るの？たまにはうちが君を見てほしい、みお。
Why are you only looking at other guys sometimes? I want you to look at me, Mio.
え、別に君のことが好きとか、そういうのじゃないけど、
Wait, it's not like I like other guys or anything.
うちも君も好きっていうか、君が好きなのか！
Wait, I like you too, I guess? I like you, I guess?
それってつまり、お刺身ってこと！？
That means... "Sashimi"?
さしみお
Sashimio.
やり切った！ありがとう！
We did it! Thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
いや、いい曲にしあがってたね。
Man, it turned into such a good song!
いい曲だったよ。
It really was a good song.
ねえ、頑張って歌詞考えてくれて本当にありがとうね、2人とも。
Man, thank you both so much for working hard to think of the lyrics!
こちらこそありがとう！楽しかった！
Thank you so much! It was so fun!
めっちゃ楽しかった！りしゅうさんもね、こんなカオスな曲をさ、
It was super fun! Lishiu-san too, right?
まとめ上げて下さりましてね、先生が！ありがとうございます！
You managed to put it together so well! Thank you so much, sensei!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
え、この歌はね、後日動画でも登場しますのでね、ぜひね。
And this song will also appear in videos later on, so please look forward to it!
えー！そうなの？
Eh? Really?
めっちゃ楽しみじゃん！
It's so exciting!
楽しみ！
So much fun!
バックダンスもね、初めてやったけどめっちゃ楽しかったよね！
And backup dancing too, although it's my first time, it was so much fun, right?
本当！
Really!
ここここ！
Right here, right here!
みみ！みみ！
Mimi! Mimi!
みみみみみみ！
Mimi, mimi, mimi, mimi!
これが楽しみだよ。やたら楽しそうだった。
This is so much fun! It's been so much fun.
カメラさんもちゃんと拾ってくれてたし。
Camera-san even picked us up properly.
でもカメラさん、どっちが振り向くんだってなって。
Wait, camera-san, which way are you facing? That's what I was thinking!
確かに、確かに。
That's true, that's true.
あー、楽しかったね。やりきったわ。
Ah, it was fun! We did it!
え、ていうか、ころさんは？
Wait, what about Korone-san?
ころさん帰ってこなくない？
Korone-san, won't you come back?
え、じゃケーキは？
What about the cake?
あ。
Ah.
もう食べてるかもしれないから、うちらの誕生日ケーキ先に探しておこうよ。
She might have eaten it already, so let's look for our birthday cakes first!
あー！じゃあ、みおちゃん、みおちゃんはここにまだいないの？
Yeah! Let's go! Mio-chan, Mio-chan is not here yet.
あ、分かった。まあ、うちらにラテ欄もあるもんね。うんうん。
I see. Well, Mio-chan has her own-
そうだよ。じゃあ、スバルたちは一足ケーキにありつこーたき！
That's right. So, Subaru-tachi, one step to the cake! Ari-tsuko-taki!
待って待って待って！うちらのケーキなのに！
Wait, wait, wait, wait! It's our cake, but-
いなくなっちゃった。
It's gone.
で、2人ともありがとー！
And thank you, both of you!
じゃあ、うちはちょっとゆっくりするか。
Well, we'll take it slow.
へえ、きー！
Hey, key!
おー、ゆうそー！じゅーじゅーって、わー！
Yay! Good job, Tatsuto!
みおちゅー！
Mio-cho!
なんかい、あれ必要だな？
What, is that necessary?
なんか、ちょっとテンションおかしくない？大丈夫？
Somehow, isn't my tension a little weird? Are you okay?
今日は、なんと、お休みの日だけ-あ、お休みだ！だ！だ！
Today is, after all, only a holiday!
いぇい、いぇい、いぇい、いぇい、いぇい！
Yay, yay, yay, yay, yay!
いぇー！なんか、誰かいるかなと思って、きちゃったわけよ。
Yay, I thought someone might be there, so I came!
遊びに来たってこと？
You came to play?
そうそうそうそう。あ、なるほどね。
So, so, so, so. I see.
そしたらみおちゃんが。
Then Mio-chan-
まあまあ、うちいまですけれどもね。
Well, well, I have it now, though.
なんで、なんで私服なのはに、アイドル衣装な？
Why, why are you in civilian clothes? Why are you in idol clothes?
あー、まあ、ちょっといろいろ海より深い理由が。
Ah, well, it's for various reasons deeper than the ocean.
海より深いの？やばい。
Deeper than the ocean? No way.
山より高いってこと？
Higher than a mountain?
まあまあまあ、そう、そういうことかな。まあ、そういうことしとくか。
Well, well, well, that's- that's how it is. Well, that's how it is.
え？何してたの？
Eh? What were you doing?
え、もう、もう、あのね、歌ったりとかしてたんだけどさ。
Well, I was singing and stuff, you know.
え、ここで？
Eh, here?
お、まあまあ、そうだな。この格好で？この格好で？
Well, well, that's right. In this outfit? In this outfit?
うわあ、すごいね。
Wow, that's amazing.
なんか、う、歌えって言われて。
Somehow, I was told to "sing."
あ、「歌え」って言われたの？
Ah, you were told to sing?
うん、そう。
Yeah, so-
じゃあ、みおちゃんと歌いたい！
Towa, let's sing with Mio-chan!
あ、え、歌ってくれるの？
Eh, eh? Will you sing with me?
え？うん。
Eh? Yeah.
これ、あの誕生日のライブなんだけど、大丈夫？
This is a birthday live, is that okay?
あ、じゃあちょっと恥ずかしいからやめとこ。
Ah, then I'm a bit embarrassed, so stop.
なんでやねん！なんでやねん！突然やめん な！
Why did you say that? Why did you suddenly stop?
じゃあいいの？誕生日なのに？とわがでしゃばって、一緒にがんばろ！いぇーい！
Then is it okay? It's your birthday, right? Towa stepped in, let's do our best together! Yay!
いぇーい！
Yay!
じゃあ、なんかせっかくだから、とわもアイドル衣装来ちゃう？
Then, since we have the chance, Towa, will you wear an idol outfit too?
え？
Eh?
いや、切るのやめようかな。なんでやねん！
Well, you can skip it if you want. Why did you say that?
うそ、いたい！
No, I want to!
おい、いたいね！いたいいたい！
I want to, I want to!
ちょっとアイドル衣装ついでにステージも変えちゃおうかな。
Let's change our stage along with our idol outfits!
お、変えよ、変えよ、変えよ、変えよ！
Oh, change, change, change, change!
はい、いっせーの、じゃーん！
Okay, ready, go! Jump!
わあ！いぇーい！いぇーい！いぇーい！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
来ましたよ。
We're here!
いぇい！来ましたよー。
Yay! We're here!
来たぜ、いぇい！
Here we go! Yay!
とわわけでね、まあ、可愛い衣装に着替えたところで、
So, you know, we changed into cute outfits, and-
うん、緊張してきた。
Nervous, aren't you?
緊張してきたわ？緊張してきた！
Are you nervous? I'm nervous!
てか、何、何を歌うか知ってる？
Do you know what we're going to sing?
知ってるよ。知ってた。
I know! I knew it.
うん、テレパシーで通じちゃった。
I teleported and found out.
うん、あす…なんだままそのままと。
Just like that.
あの、いい感じの、あの、そう、大人の魅力を出してみた。
We brought out a good, adult charm.
あ、そういうこと？
Ah, is that so?
うん。大人の魅力じゃ、ちょっと頑張って追求していくうた…なのかな分かんないけど。
Yeah. Adult charm? Then I'll try my best to pursue it-
いや、ちゃうわ！違うかい！うん。
No, that's wrong! Is it different?
ちょっと、あの、ハッピーな感じでいきたいかな。ハッピーな感じでね！
Just, happy vibes, you know. Happy vibes!
いぇい、いぇい、いぇい！じゃあみんな盛り上がっていきましょう！
Yay, yay, yay! Let's all get hyped up!
よーい！
Yay!
というわけで、はい、次で2人で歌う曲いっちゃいましょうか！おい！
And now, let's sing the song for the two of us! Hey!
せーの！ブルークラッパー！
Ready, go! Blue Clapper!
手を上げて
Raise your hands
clap your hands 海の向こうまで
clap your hands, beyond the ocean
clap your hands 届くように
clap your hands, so it reaches you
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
ほら 一緒に
Hey, everyone together
clap your hands 空の向こうまで
clap your hands, beyond the sky
clap your hands 響きますように
clap your hands, so it echoes through
手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands
光射す ぼくたちの未来
Our glowing future
5 4 3 2 1
hololive 5th stars
始めようか さあ diving
Shall we begin? Now, diving
待っても 意味ない timing
Even if you wait, it's meaningless timing
あの魚みたいに swimming swimming
Swimming, swimming like that fish
引き寄せるの lighting
The lighting closing in
まだ見えないよ maybe
Maybe still unseen
この先には 何があるのか？
What's waiting ahead of us?
まだ早いよ take it
Still too early, take it
追い付くまで shaking
Shaking until we catch up
でもたまに 止まって thinking thinking
But sometimes stopping, thinking, thinking
maybe この好きには何があるの
Maybe, what lies inside this feeling?
まだ早いよ timing 追いつくまで shaking でもたまに止まって thinking thinking
It's still too early, timing. Shaking until I catch up, but sometimes stopping to think, think.
sinking sinking 変えてみせる change 踏み出すのさ stepping 掴んでみせるよ
Sinking, sinking. I'll show you a change, taking a step forward, I'll grasp it—
キラキラ my dream
my sparkling dream.
叶う日まで story 繋ぐから だって 君に ずっと見てほしいから
Connecting the story until the day it comes true, because I want you to keep watching me forever.
手を上げて clap your hands 海の向こうまで clap your hands 届きますように
Raise your hands, clap your hands, across the sea, clap your hands, may it reach you.
手を叩こう 手を叩こう ほら 一緒に everybody clap your hands 空の向こうまで
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands! C'mon together, everybody, clap your hands, across the sky,
clap your hands 響きますように 手を叩こう 手を叩こう 照射す 僕たちの未来
clap your hands, may it resonate. Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands, illuminating our future.
everybody clap your hands 空の向こうまで clap your hands 響きますように 手を叩こう 手を叩こう 照射す 僕たちの未来
Everybody, clap your hands, across the sky, clap your hands, may it resonate. Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands, illuminating our future.
今日はいらないブレーキ 理性 壊せ breaking 何時でもいいでしょ 四六時中
We don't need brakes today, breaking our rationality. Anytime is fine, 24/7.
君は何をfeeling? 解き放て sparking 暗闇に放つ レーザービーム
What are you feeling? Unleash the sparking, a laser beam released into the darkness.
光らせて stage 作るから だって 君にもっと見てほしいから
Making the stage shine as we build it, because I want you to watch me even more.
手を上げて clap your hands 海の向こうまで clap your hands 届きますように 手を叩こう 手を叩こう
Raise your hands, clap your hands, across the sea, clap your hands, may it reach you. Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands!
ほら 一緒に everybody clap your hands 空の向こうまで clap your hands 響きますように 手を叩こう 手を叩こう
C'mon together, everybody, clap your hands, across the sky, clap your hands, may it resonate. Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands!
照射す 僕たちの未来
Illuminating our future.
重なる wave 世界を揺らせ
Overlapping waves, shake the world!
終わりがある事 既に i know でもまだまだ 泳ぎ足りないの
I already know that everything has an end, but we still haven't had enough of swimming.
boom! give me crazy! boom! まるで lazy? boom! 次次元混ざり合うの
Boom! Give me crazy! Boom! Are we like lazy? Boom! Dimensions mingle together,
全て塗り替える blue 手を上げて clap your hands 海の向こうまで clap your hands 届きますように
painting everything blue. Raise your hands, clap your hands, across the sea, clap your hands, may it reach you.
手を叩こう 手を叩こう ほら 一緒に everybody clap your hands 空の向こうまで clap your hands 響きますように
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands! C'mon together, everybody, clap your hands, across the sky, clap your hands, may it resonate.
手を叩こう 手を叩こう 照射す 僕たちの未来 everybody clap your hands 空の向こうまで clap your hands 響きますように
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands, illuminating our future. Everybody, clap your hands, across the sky, clap your hands, may it resonate.
手を叩こう 手を叩こう 照射す 僕たちの未来
Let's clap our hands, let's clap our hands, illuminating our future.
ふう… はあ…！
Phew... Haa...!
激し… ブルーラッパーでした！
That was intense... Blue Clapper!
です！ありがとう！
Yes! Thank you!
いやあ、すごい楽しかった！
Man, that was so much fun!
疲れ取れないか？
Doesn't it wear you out?
お休み中なのにごめんね！
Sorry even though you're on a break!
いや全然、もうさ、ミオちゃんがもう呼ぶならもう行きますよ！
Not at all! If Mio-chan calls, I'll go right away!
羽を広げ…ミオちゃんのもとへ。なるほどね、羽を伸ばす。
Spread your wings... to Mio-chan's side. I see, spreading your wings.
そうそうそう。あ、ていうかそういえばさ、なんでミオちゃんさ、事務所にいたの？
That's right. Oh, come to think of it, why were you at the office, Mio-chan?
ああ、そうか。ケーキ食べようと思ってたんだよね。
Ah, right. I was thinking of eating cake.
ケーキ！あ、ハッピーバースデー！
Cake! Oh, happy birthday!
ありがとう！ありがとう！ラブユー！
Thank you! Thank you! Love you!
そうそう、そうなの。あー、ラブユー！
That's right, yeah. Ah, love you!
なんか、なんかケーキなくて。
Somehow, there was no cake.
うんうん。なんかどっかでケーキ見なかった？
Yeah yeah. Did you see cake anywhere?
あ、ケーキ？え、もしかして大きかった？
Ah, cake? Eh, was it big by any chance?
あ、そう！大きいケーキ！見た？
Ah, yeah! A big cake! Did you see it?
見たかもしれない！え、本当？
I might have seen it! Eh, really?
え、ちょっと行こっか。ちょ、ちょっと行ってきてよ。
Eh, shall we go? Go check it out for a sec.
あ、ありがとう。え、なんか、教えてどこにあったか。
Ah, thanks. Um, tell me where it was.
いなくなった。え？ケーキあったみたいですね。
She disappeared. Eh? It seems there was cake.
といいうことは、うちはもうちょっとでケーキが食べれ るってこと？
That means we'll be able to eat cake in a bit?
わかんないけど、あれ、なんか、なになに？この声は。
I don't know, but hey, what's this voice?
見聞き！はっ、巫女っち！
Mikochi! Ha, Miko-chi!
はっ、真似た！それはケーキ！
Ha, you imitated me! That's a cake!
あ、ちょっとちょっと！ほらほら、なんで持ち逃げしようとしてるの？
Ah, wait wait! Look, why are you trying to run away with it?
いや、これはね、さっき、あの、そこにねこうて置いてあったからミコがキャッチしたんだよ！
No, see, it was placed over there earlier, so I caught it, Mio!
あ、置いてあったの？
Ah, it was placed there?
ひろってきたってこと?
"Did you pick it up?"
いや、これはひろってきたというのもそんなけど
"Well, to say I picked it up is kinda..."
うん、すっごい言い訳するじゃん、うん。
"Yeah, you're making a huge excuse, yeah."
みオたんにあの誕生日プレゼントでいいかなと思ってちょっと持ってきたな。
"I thought it'd be good as a birthday present for Mio-tan, so I brought it."
本当?ありがとう、嬉しい!
"Really? Thank you, I'm so happy!"
もしかしてこれは初めて見たケーキではないってこと?
"Wait, is this not the first cake you've ever seen?"
うん、なんかね、うん、なんかずっとお預け食らってるんだよ、ケーキ。
"Yeah, like, yeah, I've been kept waiting for the cake the whole time."
あ、そうなの?じゃあミコが持ってきたねた!
"Oh, is that so? Then Miko brought it!"
よかったぁ、ありがとう!お誕生日おめでとう!ありがとう、ありがとう!
"Yay, thank you! Happy birthday! Thank you so much!"
じゃあ二人でケーキ食べちゃう?
"Shall we eat the cake together?"
うん食べよー!みこも食べていいの?
"Yeah, let's eat! Can Miko eat too?"
もちろん、もちろんどっちもね。
"Of course, of course, both of us."
あれ?どこに行ったのかな?あとはなんか塔もね。
"Huh? Where did it go? And also the tower, you know."
さっきいったね。そう、ケーキが、なんか
"You just said it. Yeah, the cake, like..."
まあ、あるって言って、どっかにいっちゃったんだけどさ、うん、なんかどこにもいなくなってたんだよね。
"Well, you said it was there, and it went somewhere, but it completely disappeared."
え、いっか、なんかフォークとか
"Eh, whatever, like a fork or..."
ここにあるのにね。
"It's right here though."
いやあ、ちょっとケーキ、せっかくならね、食べたいから、このチャンスを逃す手はないんだけど、ちょっと
"Man, I really want to eat the cake since we have the chance, I can't miss this, but..."
そうだね、じゃあここに一旦置く?うん、置くか。
"That's right, so shall we put it here for now? Yeah, let's put it."
置くか、よいしょ。
"Let's put it down, heave-ho."
いや、いいだね。可愛いよねケーキね。
"Man, how nice. The cake is cute, huh?"
ね、美味しそうだね。
"Right, looks delicious."
ケーキ。だいじょうぶみおちゃん。
"Cake. Are you okay, Mio-chan?"
すごい、誕生日おめでとうみおちゃん。
"Amazing, happy birthday, Mio-chan."
ありがとう。歌って踊ると結構ゼーゼー。
"Thank you. Singing and dancing makes me pretty out of breath."
あとさ、なんかいろいろあったのかな。
"Also, I wonder if there were various things."
おいしそう。ローラーだよ。
"Looks delicious. It's a roller."
ちょっと待って!
"Wait a second!"
なんだなんだ?
"What, what?"
トワ様?な、なんだ、魔王みたいな笑い方してさ。
"Towa-sama? W-What, laughing like a demon."
ふふっ、はーい!
"Heh, hi!"
今からね、食レポするの。しょくレポクイズ!
"Starting now, we're doing a food report. A food report quiz!"
食レポクイズー!
"Food report quiz!"
セルフSEね。はい。
"Self sound effects. Yes."
ちょ、ちょ、待って待って!
"W-W-Wait a minute!"
え、ケーキを食べたいか?
"Eh, do you want to eat cake?"
食べたーい!お誕生日だからね、食べたーい!
"We want to eat it! It's your birthday, so we want to eat it!"
ケーキを食べたいのであれば、トワの食レポのゲームに正解したらば、ならば、よいです。
"If you want to eat cake, if you answer Towa's food report game correctly, then alright."
これから、なんかよいです。凄まじい始まり方みたいな。
"From now on... That's an intense way to start."
猫死ぬの?
"Cat dies?"
え?みこ先輩は死ぬ。なんでだよ!
"Eh? Miko-senpai dies. Why!?"
まさか猫死ぬのおかしいだろ!おかしくだろ!聞いてきたから
"No way, a cat dying is absurd! That's weird! You heard it..."
死ぬのが答えおかみたいな。
"Die is the answer, or something."
なるほど、なるほどね。
"I see, I see."
はい。え、なんクイズっていった?
"Yes. Eh, what quiz did you say?"
食レポクイズです。食レポクイズ?はい。
"It's a food report quiz. A food report quiz? Yes."
レポでいけんの、トワ様?
"Can you do it with a report, Towa-sama?"
いや、できるよ。おー!
"No, I can do it. Oh!"
本当に?なんと、今日はね、ライン越えしない程度にね、
"Really? Today, to a degree that doesn't cross the line..."
あの、食レポをしていきたい。トワ様の食レポでライン越えて逆日野でやる。
"Um, I want to do a food report. Towa-sama's food report crosses the line and does it in reverse."
どういうことなんだいった。いや、ちょっと語彙力が足りなさすぎて、
"What does that mean? No, my vocabulary is too lacking..."
ちょっと語彙力、トワの小さい辞書から引き出せ、引きずり出した。
"Vocabulary, pulled out from Towa's small dictionary."
小さい辞書。
"Small dictionary."
がんばって、今がんばってる。
"Do your best, I'm doing my best."
引きずり出してるってこと?
"You're dragging it out?"
いや、今トワの目の前には、もうあるんです。
"No, right in front of Towa, it's already there."
食材が。
"The ingredients."
あ、これから食レポする食材があるってこと?そうなんです。
"Ah, so there are ingredients to report on? That's right."
部屋で一人ぼっちでこの食材を食べて皆にお知らせをするという。
"Eating this food alone in her room and letting everyone know."
ちょっと一人ぼっちなの?一人ぼっちの寂しいやつです。
"You're all alone? A lonely person all alone."
涙はないです。あれの反応もなしに生きています。
"There are no tears. Living without any reaction to that."
はい。なんかちょっと美味しそうだね。
"Yes. Sounds a bit delicious."
美味しそうだね、なんかね。うんうん。
"Looks delicious, huh, yeah. Yeah, yeah."
いやいやいや。え、じゃあ、じゃあ、
"No no no. Eh, then, then..."
早速だけど、じゃあ初めてもらっていい?ケーキ食べたいし。
"Quickly though, can we get started? We want to eat cake."
はーい!
"Hia!"
じゃあ、やりたいと思います。お願いします!
"Then, I'd like to do it. Please!"
いやあ、まず、ていうかなんでこんなちょっと地獄なだけ と、なんか手が震えてるよ。
"Man, first of all, why is this a bit hellish, my hands are shaking."
なんで?大丈夫ですよ、まず一口目いきたいと思います。
"Why? It's fine, first I'd like to go for the first bite."
はい。
"Yes."
なに、どん、どんなもの、こ、こんな?
"What, wh-what kind of thing is this?"
あ、食ってる、食べてる。
"Ah, she's eating, she's eating."
はじめてにゃ。あ、これティッシュよ。
"First time, nya. Ah, this is tissue."
こっちしよ?ティッシュよ、すいません。
"Is it this? Tissue, excuse me."
あ、食べてる。じゃあ、まずそうですね。
"Ah, she's eating. Well, first of all..."
天使のような、て、天使?
"Like an angel... an angel?"
ふわふわな?
"Fluffy?"
うえばさまーん?
"Upper-basaman?"
ん?いや、ふわふわな、かなたんってこと?
"Hmm? No, fluffy, you mean Kanatan?"
いや、もう、それ、それはゴリラよ。あ、ゴリラじゃなかった。
"No, that, that's a gorilla. Ah, not a gorilla."
かなたんだんの見てるだけで。やにやに。
"Just watching Kanatan makes me grin."
いやいやいや、大丈夫、大丈夫。ニヤニヤしてるから。
"No no, it's fine, it's fine. She's grinning."
いや、ふわふわな、うんうん。
"No, fluffy, yeah yeah."
そうですね、あの、布団と、
"That's right, um, and a futon..."
布団の間に布団の間に
"Between the futon, between the futon..."
そうですね、あの、ほどよい甘さの、そうですね、あの、
"That's right, um, with moderate sweetness, that's right, um..."
なんて、言えばいいんですか?あの、雲が、雲が入ってて、
"How should I put it? Um, clouds, clouds are in it,"
これ、味で言うと本当に何て言うんだろう、声の、あ、違う、声の
"Speaking of taste, what on earth is it? The voice, ah no, the voice..."
もう、あの、精神を思い出すような。
"It makes you remember your spirit..."
下手なやつですね、食レポ下手じゃなくて、ゆとりが出ちゃって。
"She's bad at this, not that she's bad at food reporting, but she got nervous."
のせにしないでよ、
...not to mention,
受け取れたもんだ、で、
wait, received that much?
で、あの、ふわふわの、布団の間に、
And, you know, during that fluffy...
その、青春の中、心は、その青春のような、うん、その、なんかも、ほ、もう、
its youth, like, heart was...
もう、そういうことよ。
already, you know, stuff like that.
で、
And...
なるほど、わかった、わかった、わかった。
Oh, I see, I see, I see.
なに、なに、なに?
What, what, what?
あと、あとは、え、ない、いいよ、ショートケーキ。
Also, also, what?
ショートケーキ、今?
Shortcake, right now?
いや、ちゃう、ちゃう、ちゃう、ちゃう。
No, no, no, no.
違うんだ!
It's different!
布団と布団っていうかさ。
I mean, a futon is a futon, you know?
いや、まあ、まあ、まあ、まあ、あ、じゃあ、わかった、わかった。
Yeah, well, well, well, well.
はい、どうぞ、どうぞ。ショートケーキ、ショートケーキ、8、8、8、8。
Shortcake, shortcake, right?
えっ、違うのかよ?
Wait, no, that's different.
じゃなくて、ちょっと聞いてよ。
Listen to me for a second.
その間に、その間に、もうピチピチの、ピチピチの、
In between that...
南国のような、
like, southern...
南国のような、そういうなんか、もう、はじける感じのものが、はじける感じの、
South-country-like...
お布団の間に?
between the futons?
なんだろう、そうそうそう、その青春のような感じのが、そこ手でぎゅっと。
What do you mean?
え、どういうことだよ?
Wait, what does that mean?
待って、待って、待って、待って、待って。
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
布団って言ったじゃん。
You had a futon, right?
言ったけどさ。
Yeah, I did, but...
え、うそでしょ?
Wait, really?
終わった?
Is it over?
いや、うまいやろ。
You're good at this.
終わったってこと?
You mean it's over?
終わったのかもしれない。
It might be over.
うそ。
Really?
忘れ去ったってこと?
"Forgot" means it's over?
忘れ去ったってことかもしれない。
"Forgot" might mean it's over.
他に何か言わなくていいの?
Is there anything else I shouldn't say?
えー!
Eh?
あ、じゃあ。
Ah, okay.
あ、じゃあみこ、マンゴープリン!
Ah, then Miko, mango pudding!
はい、ということでね、
Alright, so, you know...
待て!
Wait!
ごめん!
Hey!
えっ、そういうことじゃないの?
Wait, so that's not it?
まあ、そういうことで、まあ、あの誰も正解しなかったら、行けたら、
So, like...
あ、正解はね、正解はフルーツサンドでした!
Wait, if nobody got it right...
フルーツサンド!
Fruit sand!
いや、もう、あの、ほら、あの、恋の感じが出てたでしょ?
Well, I mean...
出てねえよ!
It didn't!
どこがそんな感じって?
Did that feel like love?
出てないか。
It didn't!
出てないよ。
Wait, no.
いや、でも、ケーキはちょっと無理だ。
Well, but the cake is a bit impossible.
あげられねえ。
We can't give it to you.
あ、そっか。
Ah, I see.
ケーキは、そう、失敗したからね、あげられませーん。
Cake is...
そうなの。
That's right.
だからダメなんだよー。
So we can't give it to you.
残念。
Too bad.
じゃあ、ケーキは、ま、もらっちゃいますしなら、えっ、ありがとう。
Then, can we get the cake?
没収ってこと?
You mean you're claiming it?
没収だー!
It's confiscated!
待って待って待って、正解はそうだ、ケーキ壊せろ!
Wait, let's smash the cake!
失敗したー。
We messed up.
ごめんね、みおちゃん、みこちゃんが。
Sorry, Mio-chan and Miko-chan.
正解すれば食べれたかもしれないのに。
If we did it right, we might have been able to eat it...
本当になくなっちゃった。
It's completely gone.
ごめんね、みんな。
Sorry, everyone.
でも、マンゴープリンは違うだろう。
But mango pudding is different, right?
うん。
Yeah.
それはそうかもしれないけど。
Well, that might be true.
えっと、というわけでね、ええ。
So, you know...
我々不正解だったので、はい。
Since we were both wrong...
ケーキは残念ながら食べれないんだけど、局も食べれない。
Cake, unfortunately we can't eat it, but...
いや、そうなんだよ。
Yeah, that's how it is.
でもさ、正解来てくれたからさ、一緒に歌いたいんだよね、一緒に。
But since you came for the correct answer...
え?一緒に歌いたい!
Eh? You want to sing?
やった!やった!歌う!
Yay! Yay! We'll sing!
というわけで、じゃあ、ちょっと、はい、何ですか?
So, hey, what is it?
歌いたい!
We want to sing!
わかりました。
Oh, I see.
はい、入った。なるほどね。オッケー、承知しました。
Alright, got it.
じゃあ、お聞きなさい。
Listen up.
じゃあ、えっと、二人で歌う曲一応、聞いてるかな?
So, the song we're going to sing together...
聞いてる!お!
We're listening! Oh!
じゃあ、二人で、うん。
Then, two of us...
じゃあ、この曲は「せーの」って言ったら「せーの」で言ってくれる?
If I say "Ready," will you say "Ready" too?
はい!はい!
Yes! Yes!
じゃあ、二人でこの曲歌います。
Then, the two of us will sing this song.
せーの!
Ready...
パッピパッピーデイ!
Poppy Pappy Day!
POPPY PAPPY DAY
作詞・作曲:吟(BUSTED ROSE)
Lyrics & Music: Uta (BUSTED ROSE)
指合わせしましょーよ 使うのは指一本
Let's point at each other using just one finger!
1+1=2 二人で一緒に
1 + 1 = 2, together as two!
仲良ピース 仲良ピース ピース ピピッピーピース
Matchy-matchy peace, peace, pi-pi-pi!
中指立てるんだよ 退屈な世界
Let's lock our middle fingers in this boring world.
これからも一緒だよ ずっとずっと
We'll be together from now on, forever and ever!
仲良しこよしの ダーリン ダーリン
Our matching peace signs, darling, darling!
ぽかぽか天気 公園に出かけよ
Sunny weather, let's head out to the park.
鬼ごっこ、しーそーげーむ 何しようっか♡
Playing tag, hide-and-seek, what should we do?
思い出全部一緒じゃなくちゃいや！
We have to share all our memories together!
楽しみ無限大！早く行こう！
Infinite fun, let's go quickly!
宝探しはしないの？
Aren't we going treasure hunting?
目の前に君がいる もう見つかってるよ
You're right in front of me, I've already found you.
今日も二人で 笑顔のピース集めて
Today too, gathering smile pieces together,
思い出つくるんだよ すみしー世界
making memories in this lovely world!
POPPY PAPPY DAY!
はぁ～
Ah...
はーい！
Hai!
というわけでね、えー、皆さん、
Well, everyone,
誕生日のライブ、いかがでしたでしょうかー！
how was your birthday live?
楽しんでもらえましたか？
Did you enjoy it?
ここでですね、あの、少し告知をさせていただきたいと思うんですけれども、
Now, I'd like to make a little announcement.
みんな良いでしょうか？
Is everyone ready?
良いか？
Ready?
はい！
Yes!
あ、すごく楽しかった。うんうん、良かった良かった！
It was so fun. Yes, I'm so glad!
あ、あ、ちょっと喉なっちゃったけど。
Ah, my throat got a bit...
あ、いいよ！オッケー！ありがとありがと！
It's fine! Okay, thank you!
というわけで、
So,
なんと、誕生日記念グッズが発売されるので、こちらご覧くださーい！ドーン！
birthday merchandise will be on sale, so please check it out! Ta-da!
はい、えー、誕生日記念セットです！
So, this is the birthday commemorative set!
で、こちらはですね、グッズがご一緒に来まして、大神ミオミニアルバム「Howling」。え、なんとですね、今回、オリジナル曲から真面目なやつが出るんですけど、それが「Howling」というタイトルなので、こちらですね！はい！
And this time, the original song is called "Howling", so here it is!
ミニアルバムこちらを、
Mini-album here,
えー、3曲収録されております。
it includes 3 tracks.
そして、この5つのなかの、色々紹介していくんだけど、まず、ジャケットポスター、
Now, I'll introduce each of the 5 items. First is the jacket poster.
これは、泉パパに描いてもらった！イラストになってます。はい。
This was drawn by Izumi Papa, it's an illustration!
あ、そしてCDなんだけど、そのCDが、表面はこのハウリングのめちゃくちゃかっこいいよね！そうなの、お父さんがすごいスピードで描いてくれたこのイラストめちゃくちゃかっこいいんです。
And the CD, the cover is super cool for "Howling"! Yes, Izumi Papa drew it so fast, this illustration is super cool.
このジャケットイラストプラス、
This jacket illustration plus...
裏面のジャケ裏は、えー、先ほど歌った曲の、はい、こちらですね、え、パンジャめのなめせ、なめせ先生に書いていただいた、え、イラストになります。うちがわんわんわんわん言ってる曲になります。はい。パンジャめのなめせ先生、ありがとうございます！はい。
the back is drawn by Namame Sensei, the illustration where we're going "wan wan wan wan"! Thank you, Namame Sensei!
そして、えー、次はこちらジャケットポスターですね。こちらも付いておりますので、ぜひお部屋に飾ってください。
And next is the jacket poster, this is also included so please decorate your room with it!
お次、こちらアクリルジオラマスタンドということで、え、なんとこちらですね、背景そして地面があって、こう海にうちがこう、浮き輪で浮いてて後ろの水しぶき、そしてカワちゃんとタイガー、そしてスバルのアヒルが全部バラバラになってて、こう、奥行きのあるアクリルスタンドになってます。
Next is this acrylic diorama stand! It has a background and ground, and Mio is floating in the sea, with water splashes behind, and Kawa-chan, Tiger, and Subaru's duck all separated, making it a 3D acrylic stand.
それも泉パパが描いてくれました！泉パパ大活躍ありがとう！すごい可愛いイラストだよ。
Izumi Papa drew this too. Thank you for your hard work, Izumi Papa! It's such a cute illustration.
はい。そして次次はですね、こちら、え、かもちゃめ先生のイラスト、いつもね、動くイラストを描いてくださってるかもちゃめ先生に描いていただいた、え、ラバーキーホルダー、こちらがですね、なんとボイスが出るんです。
And next is this Kamochame Sensei's voice rubber keychain! This keychain actually speaks!
これね、ポチッと押すとね、あの、5種類のボイスがランダムででるっていうキーホルダーになってまして、今日持ってこようと思ったんだけど、ちょっと忘れちゃって、
You press it, and 5 types of voices will play randomly! I wanted to bring it today, but I forgot.
え、その中には、え、みおよよよみみみみみだとか、あとは、お刺身ってことー？とか、そういうようなうちのね、うちらしい言葉が5種類入ってます。よかったらみんな押して楽しんでみてください。結構音大きいので、あの、周りにいっぱい人がいる時とかは、結構みんな「はっ」ってなっちゃうかもしれないけど、はい。ぜひ、これはぜひぜひゲットして欲しい品です。はい、お次の品。
Inside, there are lines like "Mio, mio, mio, mio, mio" or "Here is some sashimi for you" - 5 kinds of phrases in Mio's voice. I hope you'll press it and enjoy it!
はいこちら、え、ミオの部屋着とおそろロングTシャツー！パフパフ！これはねえ、絶対出したかったんだよねえ。これはね、LサイズとXLサイズの2サイズ展開となってまして、え、うちがね、あの、パーカーの下に来ている、えっと、なんていうの？部屋着みたいなやつなんだけど、これを、あの、男の人も着れるようにデザインをね、あの、シンプルにさせてもらって、作らせてもらいました。
And here, Mio's loungewear and loose long T-shirt! Puff puff! I really wanted to release this! It comes in two sizes, L and XL. It has a loose fit below the hoodie, a loungewear-like design that is simple so guys can wear it too, we made it simple.
はい、こちらみんなね、うちとおそろいの部屋着にしてもらってもいいですし、これだったらね、シンプルなんでお外に着ていってもね、かっこいいんじゃないかなって思います。ぜひいっぱい着てください。そしてお次、え、フルセットをご購入いただくと、え、こちらの泉パパのジオラマアクリルスタンドの、え、イラストのポストカードがついてきます！うちの箱押し、箱押し？箱押しサインが入って、であとはメッセージも複製で入っているので、ぜひぜひチェックしてみてください！はい。
Everyone can match with Mio, or even wear it outside since it's simple. Please get one! And next, if you buy the full set, you get a postcard with Izumi Papa's illustration, box-pressed signature and replicated message!
というわけで、以上グッズの紹介
And with that, that's the merchandise introduction!
でしたー！長い時間ありがとうございましたー！
That's it! Thank you so much for hanging out with me!
そして
And...
ブースのページは、22時からオープンして、
Um, the Booth page opens at 10:00 PM,
購入開始は22時10分からなので、
and purchases start at 10:10 PM,
あ、もう購入が、たぶんスタートしてる？
oh, so purchases might already have started?
形なんですかね？
Is that how it works?
たぶんね、あの、概要欄が更新すると概要欄にあのブースのURLとか出てくると思うんですけど、
Probably, um, when the description updates, the Booth URL and such should appear there,
はい！URL更新すると出るので、
yes! When you refresh the URL, it will appear,
ま、もしくはあの、ホロライブの公式グッズこちらっていうURLから飛べますのでね、ぜひ皆さんチェックしてみてください！
or, um, you can jump from the URL that says "Hololive official merch is here," so everyone please check it out!
バラバラでも売ってまーーす！
They're also sold separately!
はい、そして、最後に、え、うちがもう1曲オリジナル曲を披露させていただきたいんですが、そちらの曲の紹介も少しさせていただきます。
Yes, and finally, um, I'd like to perform one more original song, so I'll also introduce that song a bit.
え、Howlingという曲なんですが、まず、え、作曲、作詞作曲をしてくださった方のご紹介をさせていただきます。
Um, the song is called "Howling." First, um, let me introduce the person who wrote the lyrics and music.
あ、もう買った？みんな？
Ah, did you guys already buy it? Everyone?
あ、ありがとありがと！
Ah, thank you, thank you!
はい、それではスライドお願いします！
Yes, then slide please!
ZAQ（ざっく）
[ZAQ]
はい、え、ZAQさんという中二病でも恋がしたい！という作品のオープニング主題歌や、映画のオープニング主題歌も作っていらっしゃる。
Yes, um, ZAQ-san, who created opening theme songs for works like "Love, Chunibyo & Other Delusions!" and movies.
ま、あのね、結構女性の方ですごくキャッチーなメロディの作るのがすごいキラキラした草音源を作るのが得意な方なんですけれども、
Well, you know, she's a woman who's really good at making super catchy melodies and sparkly sounding tracks,
知ってる方もきっといるよね？
so I'm sure some of you know her, right?
あ、ZAQさん知ってる知ってる！
Ah, you know ZAQ-san? Oh!
あ、そうなんだ！
Ah, is that so!
いや、本当に、あの、この曲を書いていただいた時に、すごい、最初もう最初の方からもう、わあすごい！すごい天才的みたいな、本当いい曲だなあって思ったので、
Really, um, when she wrote this song for me, right from the very beginning I thought, "Wow, amazing! It's like pure genius," it's such a great song,
みんなに早く聴いてほしくてずっと匂わせてました（笑）。
so I kept teasing you all because I wanted you to hear it quickly (laughs).
はい、というわけで、うちが最後にHowlingを披露させていただきまして、今回は誕生日ライブ終わりにしたいと思います！それでは聴いてください、うちのオリジナル楽曲になります、「Howling」！
Yes, with that, I will perform "Howling" as the final song, and conclude this birthday live! So please listen to it, my original song, "Howling"!
信じまとい 響いてよ My howling
Enveloped in belief, echo out, my howling!
どどど 流れてく風景 切な気だな 日々の中で
Flowing on and on, the scenery feels so bittersweet amidst everyday life.
差し伸べられた手は優しく 孤独にひた走る熱も 夜風に逆ラッテ
The hand extended to me is gentle, and the heat rushing through my solitude defies the night breeze.
創造的切ったから 君に会って気付く 独りじゃない！
Because I carved out creativity, I met you and realized I'm not alone!
射光、瞬きは声が 突き刺さり響く
Light and blinking, voices pierce through and echo.
つまづく道 金色の群れ ともに嘆く夜
Stumbling paths, a flock of gold, nights of grieving together.
遠く電波する思いは 心強くて 俯きを入れよ 後ろに君がいるから
Feelings transmitting far away give strength. Look up, because you are behind me!
私は迷わない 光差す道へ
I won't get lost, toward the path where light shines.
無力だから 仲間を求め 超えるから 火を灯して
Because I am powerless, I seek companions and overcome, so light a fire.
変化と共に見かしてく この現実は 誰もすら ない 信じるとそう決めているから
This reality changing along with it—no one even... because I've decided to believe in you.
どんな異常気象も 乗り越えられるよ
Any abnormal weather or hardship, I can overcome it.
月光 この闇に唯一 リンド咲く花
Moonlight, the only gentian flower blooming in this darkness.
嘘なのかな 憧れなのかな 抜け合う夜空
Is it a lie? Is it longing? A night sky weaving together.
大地を駆け抜ける 私 時期が突き抜ける この物語り 単純な未来じゃない
Running across the earth, I break through time. This story is not a simple future.
湧き立つ情熱 この声に載せよう
Let's put boiling passion into this voice.
空飛ぶ羽なくても 手は繋げられたから この運命を絵...
Even without wings to fly, we were able to hold hands, so painting this destiny...
静寂に響いてよ my howling
Let my howling echo in the silence
連綿と流れていく風景
The scenery flowing steadily and endlessly
刹那的な日々の中で 差し伸べられた手は優しく
Amidst these fleeting days, the hand extended was gentle
鼓動に滴る微熱の予感
A premonition of fever dripping into my heartbeat
風に逆らう そう生きてきたから
I've lived pushing against the wind, so
君に会って気付く「もう独りじゃない」
Meeting you made me realize "I'm no longer alone"
無力だから仲間を求め
Seeking companions because of my powerlessness
凍えるから火を灯して
Lighting a fire because of the freezing cold
変化とともに進化していく
Evolving along with changes
この顛末はだれも知らない
No one knows how this outcome will end
君を信じるとそう決めているから
Because I've decided to believe in you
どんな異常非異常も乗り越えられるよ
I can overcome any anomaly or emergency
月光 この闇に唯一 凛と咲く華
Moonlight, the only flower blooming dignifiedly in this darkness
恐れなのか 憧れなのか 向き合う夜空
Is it fear, or is it longing? Facing each other under the night sky
Listen to my howling...
狼が止まることはない
The wolf will never stop